RYAN MURPHY

LOCATION: Middletown, CT 06457 | PHONE: 860-916-0190 | EMAIL: TheDecoder007@gmail.com

LINKEDIN: https://www.linkedin.com/in/ryan-murphy-b03435254/

GITHUB: https://github.com/TheDecoder007

PORTFOLIO: https://thedecoder007.github.io/3d-react-portfolio/

Summary

My passion is developing cutting edge experiences in the metaverse and Web3. Experience includes 2 years working for The Last Slice Collective, a full cycle development studio for high profile clients in the Metaverse. Successes include builds for Samsung, Netflix, and Sandstorm among many others. I love the prospects of web3 & the metaverse, building apps, and constantly expanding my knowledge of coding languages. Projects also include full MERN stack, API's, and more. Strong leadership experience with proven success in team management, strategic operations, business development, and customer service.

Technical Skills

Languages: HTML, CSS, Node, JavaScript, MERN, React, TypeScript

Frameworks: Bootstrap, React-Bootstrap, Bulma

Projects

SandStorm

Link to Github: https://github.com/last-slice/sandstorm-hq

Link to Project: https://play.decentraland.org/?position=50%2C-84&realm=artemis&island=14ozf

- Lead dev for building the HQ of Sanstorm in the metaverse
- Advisory to client on what is possible in the metaverse, and going beyond expectations
- Communication and coordination to meet deadlines with 5 other members of team all working remotely
- Sign in as guest to see the build

Decentraland

Link to Github: https://github.com/TheDecoder007/VoiceBox Lawn

Link to Project:

https://play.decentraland.org/?position=142%2C106&realm=unicorn&island=I59kf

- Decentraland is one of the premier metaverses, which uses Typescript and the Decentraland SDK to build game-like experiences
- Experience on several large projects with global corporations, building their metaverse scene to specification
- This is a personal build, where I test and implement advanced techniques using the SDK
- Sign in as a guest to see the build

WeTravelToo

Link to Github: https://github.com/TheDecoder007/weTravelToo

Link to Project: https://we-travel-too.herokuapp.com/

- Full MERN stack app. Create accounts, JWS token verification, password hashing. Once verified, other options become available only to users.
- Responsibilities: Project Manager. Included full front-end design and functionality using react-bootstrap, and back end code for Mongo and Express. Team management.
- Full MERN stack, react-bootstrap, fully responsive

Work History

Programmer, Consultant, Scene Development – Last Slice Collective, Worldwide 2020-Present

- Full cycle Web3 development studio for high profile clients in the Metaverse. Conception to completion. 3D models, wearables, programmers, web builders, smart contracts, NFT technology, token gating
- Client list includes Samsung 837x, Netflix, Playboy, Wall St. Bets, and many others.
- Lead Developer on SandStorm.co project, in the metaverse Decentraland.

Director of Operations, La Boca Inc. Middletown, CT, USA 2008-Present

- Developed and supervised standard operating procedures and managerial assignments.
- Innovated new ideas to drive business, with a significant increase recorded each year.
- Guided ownership towards new technologies available for website, POS(Toast) and integration of 3rd party delivery companies. Thorough knowledge of back end, programming, and design.
- Onboarded said technologies, maintained their operation, implemented procedures and training for staff on usage.
- Resolved customer complaints effectively while maintaining positive customer relations.
- Interpretation of constantly changing guidelines during Covid and restructuring operations effectively.

Skills: Team Leadership \cdot Project Management \cdot Customer Experience \cdot Critical Thinking \cdot Operations Management

Recreation Director, KidsPeace National Centers of Georgia. Carrolton, GA, USA 2004-2007

- Coordinated with unit managers to schedule daily, weekly, and monthly activities and outings for 60 troubled teens.
- Established relationships and applied for grants with area programs for ongoing free admission for clients and staff .
- Developed and exceeded departmental goals and objectives with procedures for implementation.

Skills: Crisis Intervention · Student Counseling · Program Development · Team Coordination · Event Planning

Education

Certificate in Full Stack Web Development: University of Connecticut. Remote

 24-week intensive program dedicated to designing and building web applications. Skills learned include HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, Node.JS, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, API's, Handlebars, React, and GraphQL

University of West GA: Carrollton, GA. 2002-2005 Philosophy, Criminology.

Central Connecticut State University: New Britain, CT. 2000-2002

Philosophy, Religious Studies